Finding Aid for the Stanley F. Pamphlet Horn Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Stanley F. Pamphlet Horn Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0668
8.82 linear_feet
Scope and Content Note
The Stanley F. Horn Pamphlet Collection (1782-1978) includes material ranging over a wide variety of subjects, from an early (1870) printed poem of Bret Harte to rules for dueling to an 18th century pamphlet by Thomas Paine. The most extensive part of the collection pertains to the Civil War and Tennessee history. There are many 9th century pamphlets dealing with the election and presidency of Andrew Jackson. There are also numerous materials pertaining to the Civil War, published both during the war and in the years following it.
This collection includes a small book of poetry, hand-written, illustrated with watercolors, and bound in needle-point covers, hand-made by a Tennessee woman during the Civil War. Many other materials relate to Robert E. Lee and Abraham Lincoln.
The collection also includes many materials dealing with Andrew Jackson and the Battle of New Orleans, Middle Tennessee and the city of Nashville.
The 21 boxes of the collection cover approximately 8.757 linear feet. The materials are arranged alphabetically by authors’ last names.
Biographical Sketch
Stanley Fitzgerald Horn (1889-1980) was a native of Nashville, Tennessee. In 1906, he graduated from Fogg High School and, although he was a self-educated scholar, he received an honorary Doctor of Literature from the University of Chattanooga and was made an honorary member of the Alpha Chapter of Phi Kappa Beta at Vanderbilt University.
Stanley Horn was the owner and editor of The Southern Lumberman, a lumber industry trade publication, and author of several works on Civil War subjects, most notably, Boy’s Life of Robert E. Lee, and The Army of Tennessee: A Military History. He was a life member of the Tennessee Historical Society, serving as president of that organization from 1942-1953 and again from 1961-1965, and was also appointed State Historian, after serving as chairman of the Tennessee Civil War Commission from 1961-1965.
He accumulated during his lifetime a cohesive and comprehensive collection of works on the Civil War and Tennessee history. Horn also took an active role in the preservation of historic homes and sites. He was very involved in the cultivation of irises, the State Flower of Tennessee, and served as judge for the American Iris Association.
After his accidental death in 1980, his extensive library was given to Vanderbilt University.
- Abernathy, Elizabeth Denty. The Abernathy Family, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Adair, John and Jackson, Andrew. Letters of General Adair and General Jackson, Relative to the Charge of Cowardice, 1817 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Adams, Charles Francis. The Confederacy and the Transvaal, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Adams, Charles Francis. Lee’s Centennial: an Address by Charles Francis Adams, 1907; (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Adams, J. Lewis. Old Purdy: The History of the First County Seat of McNairy County, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Addresses on the Presentation of the Sword of Andrew Jackson to the Congress of the United States, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agee, Rucker. Forrest–Streight Campaign of, 1863, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Albaugh, William A., III and Steuart, Richard D. Confederate Swords, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Alexander, Edward P. Jefferson and Kosciuszko: Friends of Liberty and of Man, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- All the King’s Horses, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Allen, R.R. Tennessee Books: A Preliminary Guide, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Allison, John. Dropped Stitches in Tennessee History, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Allison, Young E. The Curious Legend of Louis Philippe in Kentucky, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The Ancestral Home of James K. Polk, 1958; (2 copies) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Anderson, Mrs. John Huske. Pageant of Heroines of the Confederacy, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Appomatox Court House, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Appomatox Courthouse, National Historical Monument, Virginia, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Armes, Ethel. Stratford on the Potomac, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Arnett, Al. Massacre at Fort Nims, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Ashe, S.A. Abraham Lincoln, the Citizen, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ashe, S.A. Secession, Insurrection of the Negroes, and Northern Incendiarism, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Ashe, S.A. A Southern View of the Invasion of the Southern States and War of, 1861-65, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Automobile Tour of the Principal Battlefields in Front of Richmond (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bank of Hendersonville. 50 Years in Hendersonville, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Barbee, David Rankin. The Capture of Jefferson Davis, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Baskervill, Willliam Malone. Southern Writers, Biographical and Critical Studies: Charles Egbert Craddock (Mary Noailles Murfree), 1897 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Battlefields in Dixieland and Chickamauga National Military Park, 1928; (2 copies) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Bear, James A., Jr. Thomas Jefferson’s Book-Marks, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Beard, W.E. The Battle of Nashville, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Beard, W.E. It Happened in Nashville, Tennessee, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Beard, William E. Red letter Days in Nashville, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Bearss, Edwin C. The Fall of Fort Henry, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bell, John. An Address Delivered at Nashville, T., October 5th, 1830 Being the First Anniversary of the Alumni Society of the University of Nashville (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bell, Landon C. The Lincoln Myths Are Passing---But Slowly, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Bell, Landon C. Robert E. Lee: An Address, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Besse, S.B. C.S. Ironclad Virginia, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Binney, Horace. Speech Delivered by Horace Binney, Esq., at the Anti-Jackson Meeting, Philadelphia, 1832 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Blair, Hon. Francis P., Jr. Speech on the Acquisition of Central America, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Blanton, John O. Pre-Historic Man in Tennessee, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Bokum, Hermann, Chaplain, U.S.A. Wanderings North and South, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The Border Ruffian Code in Kansas, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Boult, Olivia W. The Continental Congress, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Bowie, Sydney J. Address of Hon. Sydney Bowie, to the United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Bowling, W.E. An Oration Pronounced upon the Occasion of the Laying of the Corner Stone of Nashville High School, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Boyd, C.F. The Civil War Diary of C.F. Boyd, Fifteenth Iowa Infantry, Parts I, II, III, IV, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Boyd, Julian P. and Hemphill, W. Edwin. The Murder of George Wythe, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Boynton, Gen. H.V. Chattanooga and Chickamauga, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Bradford, Thomas G., pr. Bradford’s Tennessee Almanac for the Year of Our Lord, 1820, 1820 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Brady. Tom P. Black Monday, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Brantley, W.H., Jr., comp. Battlefield of Horseshoe Bend in Tallapoosa County, Alabama, 1955; (2 copies) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Brices Cross Roads, National Battlefield Site, Mississippi, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Brown, A.V. A.V. Brown to his Constituents, 1826 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Burr, William Henry. Bacon and Shakespeare, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Burton, Thomas G. and Manning, Ambrose N., ed. Collection of Folklore: Folksongs, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Calfee, Mrs. Berkeley B. Confederate History of Culpeper County, n.d (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Campbell, Emmett C. Five American Poems, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Campbell, W.F. The Escape and Wandering of J. Wilkes Booth Until Ending of the Trail by Suicide in Oklahoma, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Cannon, Newton. The Reminiscences of Newton Cannon, 1st Sergeant, 11th Tennessee Cavalry, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Carr, Julian. The Hampton Roads Conference, 1917; (2 copies) (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Carter, John and Pollard, Graham. The Firm of Charles Ottley, Landon, & Co., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Casey, Powell A. The Battle of New Orleans: Louisiana at the Battle of New Orleans, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Central Committee. Address of the Central Committee Appointed by a Convention of Both Branches of the Legislature Friendly to the Election of John Q. Adams as President, 1828 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Ceremonies Attending the Sesquicentennial of the Battle of Horseshoe Bend, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Chabot, Frederick C. The Alamo, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Chalmette National Historical Park, Louisiana, 1959; (2 copies) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Chambers, Lenoir. The Whole Jackson, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Chase, Enoch Aquila. The History of Arlington, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Chattanooga, Lookout Mountain, and Battlefields (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Chickamauga Battlefield, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Chilton, Thomas. The Circular Address of Thomas Chilton of Kentucky, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Christian, George L. Abraham Lincoln: An Address Delivered before R.E. Lee Camp, No. 1, Confederate Veterans, 1909 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Christian, Marcus. The Battle of New Orleans: Negro Soldiers in the Battle of New Orleans, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- City Directory of Brownsville and Stanton, Tennessee, 1935-36 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Civil War Centennial Commission. Guide to the Civil War in Tennessee, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Claybrooke, John S., et al. Report of the President and Directors of the Tennessee and Alabama Rail Road Company, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Cockrell, Monroe F. After Sundown---When the Lightning Bugs Come, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Cockrell, Monroe. Corinth Houses, 1862 1947 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Coleman, J. Winston, Jr. Last Days, Death and Funeral of Henry Clay, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Colton, Henry E. Andrew Jackson’s Place in History, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Combs, Leslie. A Reply to General Jackson’s Letter of the 21st October, 1828---Published in the Nashville Republican (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Report of the Commissioners for the Erection of the State Capitol, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- A Confederate Bookshelf, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Confederate Congress. Resolution of the (Confederate) Congress (in Kentucky), 1861 1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Confederate Campfire Songs (and War Poets of the South) (Box 4, Folder 21)
- The Confederate Cruiser Shenandoah, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- A Confederate Soldier. U.S. “History” as the Yankee Makes and Takes It, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Connelly, Thomas Lawrence, ed. Notes and Documents---Did Davy Crockett Surrender at the Alamo?, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Cornwell, Ilene J. Footsteps Along the Harpeth, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Crabb, Alfred Leland. Andrew Jackson’s Nashville, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Craighead, Erwin. The Literary History of Mobile, 1914 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Creighton, Wilbur F. The Parthenon in Nashville, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Currier, Nathaniel and Ives, James M. The War, 1861-1865, as Depicted in Prints (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Daniel, John W. Ceremonies Conducted with the Inauguration of the Mausoleum (R.E. Lee), 1883; (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Daniel, John W. Robert E. Lee, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Daniel, John W. Oration on Jefferson Davis, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Davidson, Donald. To See Through All Things: a Coffee House Club Poem, 1964; (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Davis, Carolyn. Madison Hostess, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Deaderick, J.B. The Truth about Shiloh, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- DeFriece, Pauline Massengill. Rocky-Mount: The Cobb-Massengill Home, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Democratic Republican Committee of Allegheny, Pennsylvania. Address Friendly to the Election of Gen. Andrew Jackson, to the office of President of the United States, 1823 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- DePuy, Henry F. Some Letters of Andrew Jackson, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- DeWitt, John H. General James Winchester, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- DeWitt, Paul. Andrew Jackson and Free Masonry, 1947; (4 copies) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Dixon, Richard Remy. The Battle of New Orleans, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Dufour, Charles F. The Man on the Horse in Jackson Square, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Edwards, Harry Stillwell. Eneas Africanus, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Eisenschiml, Otto. The 55th Illinois at Shiloh, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Eisenschiml, Otto. The Chemist in Three Wars, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Ellard, Roscoe. General Lee and Journalism, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Eller, E. M., et al. The Battle of New Orleans, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Ellis, Arthur J. The Divining Rod---a History of Water Witching, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Elsemore, Moses. An Impartial Account of the Life of the Rev. John N. Maffitt, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Everett, Edward. Account of the Fund for the Relief of East Tennessee, 1864 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Ewell, Leighton. History of Coffee County, Tennessee, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Ewell, R.S. and Gen. G.T. Beauregard. The First Manassas, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Executive and Congressional Directory of the Confederate States, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Fabyan, George. The Greatest Work of Sir Francis Bacon, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Fabyan, George. Hints to the Decipherer of the Greatest Works of Sir Francis Bacon, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Facsimiles and Forgeries---a Guide to a Timely Exhibition in the William L. Clements Library, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Fain, John Tyree. Critical and Analytical Index and Genealogical Guide to Ramsey’s Annals of Tennessee, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- A Fair and Just Comparison of the Lives of the Two Candidates, Andrew Jackson and John Quincy Adams, 1828 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Farley, Ed. Soldier Life---My Diary, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Favorite Poems---A Treasure Trove of Choice Verse, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Fielder, E.D. The Story of the Alamo, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Figuers, Hardin Perkins. A Boy’s Impression of the Battle of Franklin, 1914; (a typewritten copy made in 1960) (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Fisher, Samuel R. The Burning of Chambersburg, 1864-1879 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Fitzhugh, Lester N. Terry’s Texas Rangers, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Fitzmaurice, E. Andrew Jackson---a Drama in Five Acts, 1901 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Folk, Reau E. Battle of New Orleans---Its Real Meaning, Exposure of Untruth Being Taught Young America, 1935; (3 copies) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Fontaine, Lamar. A Plea for Peace, Preparedness and Good Roads Everywhere, 1917 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Fort Donelson National Military Park, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Foster, Austin F. Counties of Tennessee, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Freeman, Douglas Southall. The Cornerstones of Stratford, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- A Freeman of the United States. An Address to the People of the United States on the Subject of the Presidential Election, 1831 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Fuller, Myron L. The New Madrid Earthquake, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Fulton, Justin D. Lincoln’s Assassins, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Gaines, Francis Pendleton. Lee: The Final Achievement (1865-1870), 1933 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Gallup, Elizabeth Well. Bi-lateral Cypher of Francis Bacon, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Gattinger, August. The Tennessee Flora, 1887 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Gayarre, Charles. A Sketch of General Jackson by Himself, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- General Washington and General Jackson on Negro Soldiers, 1863; (General Robert E. Lee’s autographed copy of this pamphlet) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Gentry, Claude. The Battle of Brice’s Crossroads, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Gills, Mary Louise. It Happened at Appomattox, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Give Us Small Books, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Gotterman, Guy. The Book of the Presidents: a Gallery of Famous Portraits, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Goodpasture, Albert V. Andrew Jackson, Tennessee and the Union, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Goodpasture, Henry and Virginia. Old Town, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Government and Doctrine of New Testament Churches, 1903 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Grand Lodge of Tennessee. Constitution and By-Laws, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Grand National Competitive Military Drill (Official Programme), 1883 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- The Great Panic: Being Incidents Connected with Two Weeks of the War in Tennessee, 1862 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Green, J.H. An Exposition of General Tricks with Cards, 1850 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Green, John Grayson. Footnote on the Proposed “Civil Rights” Program, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Green, John W. Judge Samuel Cole Williams, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Grimes, G. A Secret Worth Knowing: a Treatise on the Most Important Subject in the World; Simply to Say, Insanity, 1846 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Groesbeck, Hon. W. S. Walker’s Expedition to Nicaraqua, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Grundy, Felix and Brown, William L. Report upon.. .the Adjustment of the Boundary between this State (Tenn.) and the State of Kentucky, 1820 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Guide to Tennessee Historical Markers, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Hale, Will T. The First Tennessee Regiment, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Halley, R.A. The City of Nashville, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Hamil, H.M. Sam Davis, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Hampden. An Examination of the Charge Preferred by General Jackson Against Mr. Adams and Mr. Clay, 1827 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Hampton, Wade. Address on the Life and Character of Robert E. Lee, 1871 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Hardie Brothers. Hardie’s Historical Guide to Chattanooga, Lookout Mountain and Chickamauga National Military Park, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Hardin, J.J. Speech Reviewing the Public life and Political Principles of Mr. Van Buren, 1844 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Harkness, David J., comp. Southern Heroes, Heroines, and Legends, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Harkness, David J. Tennessee in Literature, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Harkness, David J., comp. Tennessee, “The Most interesting State”., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Harmsworth, Cecil. Dr. Johnson’s House, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Harrington, J.C. Archeology and the Historical Society, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Harte, F. Bret. The Heathen Chinese, 1870 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Harwell, Richard Barksdale. Confederate Belles-Lettres, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Henderson, Archibald. Richard Henderson: The Authorship of the Cumberland Compact and the Founding of Nashville, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Henderson, Archibald. Richard Henderson and the Occupation of Kentucky, 1775-1916 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Hensel, W.U. Robert E. Lee as a Citizen, Soldier and Statesman, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Heseltine, William G. Andersonville Revisited, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Hewitt, John Hill. King Linkum the First, a Musical Burletta as performed at the Concert Hall, Augusta, Georgia, Feb. 23, 1863, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Hiatt, Ellen Olivia Mitchell. Sequatchie Valley---a Historical Sketch, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Hill, J.B. Hills’ Tennessee Almanac and State Register, 1827 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- The Historic Blue Grass Line, 1913 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- History of the McKendree Methodist Church, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Holmes, William C. Jackson, the Statesman, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Home of Sam Davis, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Hood’s Nashville Campaign, 1964; ( Special Issue of Civil War Times Illustrated) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Horn, Stanley F. Books You may have Missed, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Horn, Stanley F. The Hermitage, 1961; (2 copies) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Horn, Stanley F. The Southern Pine Story, n.d.; (3 copies) (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Horn, Stanley F. Twenty Tennessee Books, 1958; (5 copies) (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Horn, Stanley F. Twenty More Tennessee Books, 1971; (3 copies) (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Horseshoe Bend Battle Park Association. The Importance of the Battle of Horseshoe Bend (Box 9, Folder 9)
- How to Find Interesting Places in Nashville (for Service Men), c., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Howell, Isabel. John Armfield of Beersheba Springs, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Huber, Leonard V. New Orleans at War in, 1814-1815, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Huddleston, Ed. Big Wheels and Little Wagons, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Huddleston, Ed. The Land Between the Rivers, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Hunt William Gibbs. Address on the Character and Services of De Witt Clinton, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Hunt William Gibbs. Address Delivered at the Request of the Literary Society of the University of Nashville, 1831 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Hunt, William Gibbs. An Oration in Honor of General Lafayette, Delivered in His Presence, 1825 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- An Impartial and True History of the Life and Services of Major-General Andrew Jackson, 1824 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Introducing You to the Dixie Line, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Irwin, Wallace. The Love Sonnets of a Hoodlum, 1901 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Jackson, Andrew. Andrew Jackson’s Proclamation Against the Nullification Ordinance of South Carolina, 1832 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Johns, George S. Philip Henson, the Southern Union Spy, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Jones, N.W. A History of Mount Pleasant, Especially, and the Western Part of Maury County, As He Remembers it, 1903 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Joseph Conrad, a Sketch, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Kaser, David. A Directory of the Book and Printing Industries in Ante-Bellum Nashville, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Kelley, Paul. Historic Fort Loudoun, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Kimball, Marie G. The Furnishings of Monticello, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Kincaid, Robert L. Under the Big Beech, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Kurtz, Wilbur G. The Atlanta Cyclorama of the Battle of Atlanta, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, 1959; (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Hermitage, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Ladies Hermitage Association. The Historic Hermitage Properties, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Lancaster, Frances E. Look to the Sunny Side, 1863(?). (Ms. book of verse, illustrated with original watercolors, and in hand-made needle-work binding) (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Lancaster, Robert Bolling. A Sketch of the Early History of Hanover County, Virginia, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Lanier, Sidney. Robert E. Lee: An Address, and Stratford on the Potomac by Ethel Armes, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Law, Ernest. Shakespeare’s Garden, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Lee Chapel---Washington and Lee University, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Lee Mansion National Memorial, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Lee, Robert E. Glimpses of the Past---Letters of Robert E. Lee to Henry Kayser, 1838-1846, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Lewis, Joseph N. Old Things and New, or Ancient Fables and Modern Men---a Satire, 1835 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Lewis, Lloyd. Letters from Lloyd Lewis, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Lewis, Samuel E. The Treatment of Prisoners of War, 1861-1865, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Lightfoot, W.I. The Story of the “General”, 1862 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- The Lincoln Myth, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Lincoln Sesquicentennial Commission. Lincoln Sesquicentennial, 1909-1959, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Lindquist, Orville. Common Fallacies Regarding United States History, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Lindsley, Maggie. “Maggie”---Maggie Lindsley’s journal, 1864-1865, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Lindsley, Philip. An Address Delivered.. .at the Inauguration of the President of Cumberland College, 1825 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Lindsley, Philip. Baccalaureate Address... on the Sixth Anniversary Commencement of the University of Nashville, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Lindsley, Philip. Baccalaureate Address... on the Seventh Anniversary Commencement of the University of Nashville, 1832 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Lloyd, Lord. The British Case, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 9)